Guide to the Charles Baldwin Letters, 1846-1858 MS 166
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Charles Baldwin letters
1846-1858
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Baldwin, Charles
MS 166
0.25 Linear Feet (1 folder)
The letters are legal in nature, and apparently deal with various lawsuits brought by or against Baldwin concerning land and contracts.
Biographical Note
Nothing is known about Dr. Charles Baldwin, M.D., other than that he lived in Union, Monroe County, Virginia, in the mid-1840s.
Scope and Contents
The letters are legal in nature, and apparently deal with various lawsuits brought by or against Baldwin concerning land and contracts. Several of the letters concern Baldwin's part in the estate of F.H. Petrie and whether or not Baldwin was guardian to certain relatives of Petrie. Other letters deal with cases regarding land titles in various surveys. The last letter in the collection was sent to Baldwin from a lawyer requesting immediate payment for fees and court costs for Dunlap vs. Pattison (in which Baldwin was interested) and is accompanied by court statements.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. Andrew Forest Muir, June 1965
Index Terms
Subjects
Courts
Document Types
letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Correspondence, 40128
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from F(?). H. Petrie, Rankin County, May 20, 1846, 40144 (Letter 1)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from Tho. Aigrinwall, London (England), March 30, 1847, 40143 (Letter 2)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from (?) N. Burnside, New Orleans, July 6, 1847, 40142 (Letter 3)
  - Letter to Addison Dunlap from C.R. Clifton, Jackson, Miss, November 16, 1847, 40141 (Letter 4)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from J.W. McNutt, Victoria Tx, December 26, 1853, 40140 (Letter 5)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from Michael Erskine, Victoria, Tx, January 18, 1854, 40139 (Letter 6)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from J.W. McNutt, Seguin, Tx, June 24, 1854, 40138 (Letter 7)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from J. Picknew Henderson, San Augustine, Tx, July 20, 1854, 40137 (Letter 8)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from F. Anderson, Jackson, Miss, September 19, 1854, 40136 (Letter 9)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from Shanks and Bonner, Rusk, Tx, May 26, 1855, 40135 (Letter 10)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin and Addison Dunlap from W. A(?). Bartlett, New Orleans, June 1, 1855, 40134 (Letter 11)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from Shanks and Bonner, Rusk, Tx, April 8, 1856, 40133 (Letter 12)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from Henry A. Clinch, New Orleans, February 18, 1858, 40132 (Letter 13)
  - Letter to Baldwin and Dunlap from H. A. Clinch, New Orleans, April 21, 1858, 40131 (Letter 14)
  - Letter to Charles Baldwin from H.A. Clinch, New Orleans, December 23, 1858, 40130 (Letter 15)
  - Five empty envelopes addressed to Dr. Charles Baldwin, various locations and dates., 40129 (Letter 16)